<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://krausefx.com//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://krausefx.com//" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-07-16T02:25:27+00:00</updated><id>https://krausefx.com//feed.xml</id><title type="html">Felix Krause</title><subtitle>Personal website and blog of Felix Krause</subtitle><entry><title type="html">instapipe.net - Distribute your Instagram stories</title><link href="https://krausefx.com//blog/instapipe" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="instapipe.net - Distribute your Instagram stories" /><published>2019-05-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://krausefx.com//blog/instapipe</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://krausefx.com//blog/instapipe">&lt;h2 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want to share experiences as they are happening in your life. Instagram Stories is a great way to do so, thanks to cross-posting to Facebook, Messenger and Instagram itself, allowing most people to view your stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However just like Snapchat, the platforms try to lock you in, with the content &lt;strong&gt;you&lt;/strong&gt; create. Many of my family members and close friends don’t use FB/IG daily, but still wanted to stay up to date on what I’m up to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to lack of an official API, and any kinds of integrations, the only way to access your stories is through the inofficial API the Instagram mobile- and web client use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;solution&quot;&gt;Solution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A simple web service that automatically downloads and publishes your stories on various platforms. It’s open source and fully self hosted, check it out &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/KrauseFx/instapipe&quot;&gt;on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;embed-into-websites&quot;&gt;Embed into websites&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://whereisfelix.today&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/instapipe/whereisfelixScreenshot.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Showing what you’re up to on the websites you operate is an easy way to make your online presence more personal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://whereisfelix.today&quot;&gt;On whereisfelix.today&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://krausefx.com&quot;&gt;Integrated into krausefx.com&lt;/a&gt; (desktop only)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://krausefx.github.io/instapipe/web/index.html&quot;&gt;Plain live demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Features&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Design similar to instagram.com web&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Arrow keys to go back and forth between stories&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Support for photos and videos&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Support for desktop and mobile browsers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dismiss stories using ESC key, and clicking the dimmed area&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pre-loading of the next story for instant rendering&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Basic features like rendering of the progress bar, the relative time stamp, as well as linking to your profile&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Zero dependencies, plain JavaScript, CSS and HTML in a single file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;provide-a-json-api&quot;&gt;Provide a JSON API&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course it also provides you with a JSON API, that can be used to integrate your Instagram stories into any app or service. The API includes all relevant data, including the raw image, location and the exact resolution of the media assets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/instapipe/apiScreenshot.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://instapipe.herokuapp.com/stories.json?user_id=4409072&quot;&gt;https://instapipe.herokuapp.com/stories.json?user_id=4409072&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure to manually copy &amp;amp; paste this in a new tab to avoid the cross-site scripting protection&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;telegram-group&quot;&gt;Telegram group&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of my friends don’t want to check Instagram every day, but still want to stay up to date with what I’m up to. Since they all use Telegram already, I set up a channel that automatically shows the stories I post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://t.me/joinchat/AAAAAFADGfZcXqQj3TK73A&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/instapipe/telegramScreenshot.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.me/joinchat/AAAAAFADGfZcXqQj3TK73A&quot;&gt;Telegram group&lt;/a&gt; containing all my latest stories. In particular nice to get an overview over all your most recent stories. Join it &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.me/joinchat/AAAAAFADGfZcXqQj3TK73A&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-it-works&quot;&gt;How it works&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instapipe is a simple server, that periodically fetches your most recent Instagram stories. As soon as a new story is available, it will&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Download the highest resolution photo/video and store it on your personal Google Cloud Bucket&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Store the associated metadata in a database you own, the data includes
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;24 hours signed URL to the full-resolution photo/video of your Google Cloud Storage&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The full path of the resource referencing your Google Cloud bucket&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The user ID who published the asset&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The height and width of the photo/video&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The exact time stamp of publishing&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;An &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;is_video&lt;/code&gt; flag&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The location (if a location tag is attached)
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Location Name (e.g. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Das Gym&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;lat&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;lng&lt;/code&gt; coordinates&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Post the new story into a Telegram group (&lt;a href=&quot;https://t.me/joinchat/AAAAAFADGfZcXqQj3TK73A&quot;&gt;check it out here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/instapipe/databaseScreenshot.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: center; font-size: 140%&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://instapipe.net&quot;&gt;Open instapipe.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="open-source" /><category term="instagram" /><category term="telegram" /><summary type="html">Background</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">walkwithfriends.net - Stay in touch with remote friends</title><link href="https://krausefx.com//blog/walk-with-friends" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="walkwithfriends.net - Stay in touch with remote friends" /><published>2019-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://krausefx.com//blog/walk-with-friends</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://krausefx.com//blog/walk-with-friends">&lt;p&gt;Staying in touch with close friends requires more effort when everybody lives somewhere else on the planet. Scheduling calls to catch up certainly works, but it requires time-commitment, and time zones make scheduling unnecessarily complicated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After living in NYC for a year, I ended up doing the following: If I walk somewhere for about 30 minutes, I’d text 2 friends or family members, asking if they’re available for a chat. Often one of them would end up calling me. This way, no prior planning was necessary, things felt more spontaneous and I was able to use my NYC walking time to catch up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-problems&quot;&gt;The problems&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If I text a friend &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Hey X, are you free for a call?&lt;/code&gt;, chances are they’re at work, asleep, with friends or don’t look at their phone. They’d see my message 2 hours later and reply &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Yep, sure, calling you now&lt;/code&gt;. The problem here is that by that time I’m unavailable, as the message is from 2 hours ago.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If a friend doesn’t know about this setup, they’d think I want to discuss something specific or urgent, however those kinds of calls are just to catch up and stay in touch.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Often, either none of my friends were available, or multiple responded, so it was always a tricky balance on how many friends I’d text, with the risk of both of them replying &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Yep, I'm free now&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If one friend is never available, you kind of “forget” to text them, as you already assume subconsciously that they won’t be available&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-solution&quot;&gt;The solution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Telegram bot that manages the communication and revokes messages as soon as you’re unavailable again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: center; font-size: 35px; border: none&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.me/WalkWithFriendsBot&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; style=&quot;text-decoration: none;&quot;&gt;
    🔰 Start using the bot 🔰
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table style=&quot;width: 90%&quot;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/walkwithfriends/screenshot1_framed.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/walkwithfriends//screenshot2_framed.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/walkwithfriends//screenshot3_framed.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Telegram?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It works on every major platform, including iOS, Android and macOS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It supports revoking of messages and notifications, even from the lock screen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They have a solid bots API&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Registration for new users is easy &amp;amp; fast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;more-details-on-walkwithfriendsnet&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://walkwithfriends.net&quot;&gt;More details on WalkWithFriends.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="telegram" /><summary type="html">Staying in touch with close friends requires more effort when everybody lives somewhere else on the planet. Scheduling calls to catch up certainly works, but it requires time-commitment, and time zones make scheduling unnecessarily complicated.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ending my fastlane chapter</title><link href="https://krausefx.com//blog/ending-my-fastlane-chapter" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ending my fastlane chapter" /><published>2019-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://krausefx.com//blog/ending-my-fastlane-chapter</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://krausefx.com//blog/ending-my-fastlane-chapter">&lt;p&gt;I’ve built and published iOS apps for over 8 years now. Back then the App Store review times were over 2 weeks, iTunes Connect would allow only uploads of a single screenshot at a time, there was no CocoaPods… and code signing was pretty much the same as it is today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2014, I sat in my dorm room and started working on a tool to solve some of the challenges I faced as an iOS developer. It started out by just automating the upload of screenshots and binaries to iTunes Connect. After publishing the initial version in November 2014, the iOS community seemed excited about it. It slowly went from just &lt;em&gt;deliver&lt;/em&gt;, to more tools like &lt;em&gt;snapshot&lt;/em&gt; to generate the screenshots and &lt;em&gt;pem&lt;/em&gt; to automate iOS push notifications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/fastlane-dormroom.jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast-forward to today, I’m so humbled by what &lt;em&gt;fastlane&lt;/em&gt; has grown to be. It has changed the way large iOS teams work every day, how they release their app updates, and how code signing works. It even enabled founders to start new businesses using &lt;em&gt;fastlane&lt;/em&gt; as their core foundation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/fastlane-growth.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-top: 20px; margin-bottom: 20px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m so proud to see how the community has grown around it. When &lt;em&gt;fastlane&lt;/em&gt; initially launched, it supported only 10 integrations. Today there are over 570 different integrations, from code coverage reports, beta testing services to build version management. All of this wouldn’t have been possible without the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fastlane/fastlane/graphs/contributors&quot;&gt;all the 922 contributors of the &lt;em&gt;fastlane&lt;/em&gt; main code base&lt;/a&gt;, all &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.fastlane.tools/plugins/available-plugins/&quot;&gt;the authors of the 355 third party plugins&lt;/a&gt;, as well as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fastlane/fastlane#fastlane-team&quot;&gt;fastlane core contributor team&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/fastlane-team.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was great to see &lt;em&gt;fastlane&lt;/em&gt; evolving from a small side project, into a stable, self-sustainable open source project with a strong community of contributors around it. I have no doubts that &lt;em&gt;fastlane&lt;/em&gt; will continue growing stronger in the next years, with the support of Google, as well as other companies and individual contributors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;📯 After 4.5 years it’s time for me to step away from &lt;em&gt;fastlane&lt;/em&gt;, and with that leave Google.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for what’s next, I don’t have any specific plans yet. I’ll be taking a vacation and then figuring out what problem I’m excited to solve next :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, you can stay in touch on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/krausefx&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/krausefx&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-does-it-mean-for-fastlane&quot;&gt;What does it mean for &lt;em&gt;fastlane&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google will keep investing in &lt;em&gt;fastlane&lt;/em&gt;. There will be no changes to &lt;em&gt;fastlane&lt;/em&gt; and its support system. To get help with &lt;em&gt;fastlane&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fastlane/fastlane/issues/new/choose&quot;&gt;submit an issue on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. At the same time, we will continue accepting &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fastlane/fastlane/blob/master/CORE_CONTRIBUTOR.md&quot;&gt;new fastlane core contributors&lt;/a&gt;, meaning you can get full push access to the &lt;em&gt;fastlane&lt;/em&gt; code base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;thank-you&quot;&gt;Thank you&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to thank everyone from the Twitter Fabric, Firebase and Google Cloud teams for taking &lt;em&gt;fastlane&lt;/em&gt; where it is today. I’d like to specifically call out all the contributors and the iOS community for welcoming &lt;em&gt;fastlane&lt;/em&gt; and continuing to support it. In particular &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hemal&quot;&gt;Hemal&lt;/a&gt; who believed in my vision and helped me grow personally and professionally.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="fastlane" /><summary type="html">I’ve built and published iOS apps for over 8 years now. Back then the App Store review times were over 2 weeks, iTunes Connect would allow only uploads of a single screenshot at a time, there was no CocoaPods… and code signing was pretty much the same as it is today.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How I silently changed my profile picture every other year</title><link href="https://krausefx.com//blog/continuous-delivery-for-your-profile-picture" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How I silently changed my profile picture every other year" /><published>2018-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://krausefx.com//blog/continuous-delivery-for-your-profile-picture</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://krausefx.com//blog/continuous-delivery-for-your-profile-picture">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rrhoover&quot;&gt;Ryan Hoover&lt;/a&gt; hasn’t changed his profile picture for about 10 years now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He talks about it on his blog &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@rrhoover/why-i-never-change-my-profile-pic-72de0daa2785&quot;&gt;“Why I Never Change My Profile Pic”&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People recognize you by your avatar&lt;/strong&gt;. Once changed, followers need to re-associate the new photo with your person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I very much agree: whenever someone changes their profile picture, it takes time to get used to it, and start recognizing their avatar in timelines again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;jekyll-twitter-plugin&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;That’s exactly what I think too when I come across some weird new avatar because someone changed theirs.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Todd Thomas (@toddthomas) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/toddthomas/status/968536885415981057?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;February 27, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in 2014 I took a photo at the local photo studio &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.die-fotograefin.at/&quot;&gt;Die Fotogräfin&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/profilePictures/FelixKrause2014.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; alt=&quot;Felix Krause in 2014&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-top: -10px; margin-bottom: 0px&quot;&gt;&lt;small style=&quot;margin-left: 35px;&quot;&gt;2014&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a while, I didn’t like the fact that the profile picture isn’t updated at all, but also I wanted to follow Ryan’s advice. The solution?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let’s take the exact same picture again&lt;/strong&gt;, same t-shirt, same light, same background, and same pose:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/profilePictures/FelixKrause2016.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; alt=&quot;Felix Krause in 2016&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-top: -10px; margin-bottom: 0px&quot;&gt;&lt;small style=&quot;margin-left: 35px;&quot;&gt;2016&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I silently changed the profile picture on Twitter and GitHub, and almost no one noticed, with just a few &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hemal/status/818872223268294656&quot;&gt;tweets&lt;/a&gt; calling me out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It even went that far, that &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/steipete&quot;&gt;Peter Steinberger&lt;/a&gt; covered my profile picture story in his conference talk about &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/steipete/status/998454406126424069&quot;&gt;personal branding&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using this approach, you can keep the recognition value, while making sure your current profile picture reflects on how you currently look like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the “Continuous Delivery for your profile picture” approach, I took another one this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/profilePictures/FelixKrause2018.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; alt=&quot;Felix Krause in 2018&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;margin-top: -10px; margin-bottom: 0px&quot;&gt;&lt;small style=&quot;margin-left: 35px;&quot;&gt;2018&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, almost no one noticed, with only &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lehrjulian/status/1077881037164814336&quot;&gt;one tweet&lt;/a&gt; mentioning it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here are the last 6 years in profile pictures - I plan on continuing this strategy and take a new photo every second year:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/profilePictures/ProfilePictureDiff.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="profile" /><category term="picture" /><category term="personal" /><category term="brand" /><summary type="html">Ryan Hoover hasn’t changed his profile picture for about 10 years now.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">One year nomad - a review</title><link href="https://krausefx.com//blog/one-year-nomad" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="One year nomad - a review" /><published>2018-11-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://krausefx.com//blog/one-year-nomad</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://krausefx.com//blog/one-year-nomad">&lt;div class=&quot;jekyll-twitter-plugin&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;I got rid of all my stuff and live off only a suitcase - staying in Airbnbs to explore different areas 🏡🚀 excited to live nomad life &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/nWGf7AFKiZ&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/nWGf7AFKiZ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Felix Krause (@KrauseFx) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/KrauseFx/status/928718106876305408?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;November 9, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/going-nomad&quot;&gt;Today one year ago&lt;/a&gt; I decided to get rid of my belongings and live out of a suitcase. It started as an experiment I didn’t expect to be doing for long. However after 365 days without a permanent home, I have no intentions on changing my current setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To summarize the &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/going-nomad&quot;&gt;last year’s thoughts&lt;/a&gt; on why I want to stop having a lease:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Money&lt;/strong&gt;: I only spent about 200 nights at home, making it unused for almost half the year&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Routine&lt;/strong&gt;: I don’t like having a routine when it comes places, subway and commute&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maintenance&lt;/strong&gt;: I don’t enjoy spending time setting up my apartment &amp;amp; repairing things&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most digital nomads run their own business or are freelancers/consultants. I’m a full-time Google employee working on &lt;a href=&quot;https://fastlane.tools&quot;&gt;fastlane&lt;/a&gt; here in New York City.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/krausefx&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/nomad/working-desk1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-is-the-nomad-life-so-far&quot;&gt;How is the nomad life so far?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I enjoy the flexibility of changing cities and neighborhoods as I want&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Living out of a suitcase &amp;amp; carry-on has worked surprisingly well: while I do have to limit the number of items I own, I haven’t had any troubles with it. Getting through the New York winter is a little trickier, so I keep one winter jacket in NYC, and one in Europe&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maintaining fitness progress is trickier, mostly due to the change of kitchen on every move&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One time I stayed on a boat in New York 🛥&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I got to stay in 8 different New York neighborhoods&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I always have clothes for 12 days with me&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I never forget stuff as I always have everything with me, there is no such thing as “I didn’t bring X on my trip”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/krausefx&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/nomad/from-top.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;money&quot;&gt;Money&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the main motivators of starting my nomad life was to save money. Today I did the math to see if it actually worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The last 365 days I:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spoke at a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/krausefx/speaking&quot;&gt;total of 7 conferences&lt;/a&gt;, in Russia, Austria, USA, Serbia and Norway&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Visited the SF Bay Area 3 times for team offsites and WWDC&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stayed with my family in Austria for a total of 2 months&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stayed at “home” in NYC/SF in Airbnbs for a total of &lt;strong&gt;231 nights&lt;/strong&gt; paying a total of &lt;strong&gt;$26,130&lt;/strong&gt; (63% of the nights of the year)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in my &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/going-nomad&quot;&gt;previous nomad post&lt;/a&gt;, the average rent in Airbnb can be assumed to be about $3,000 for a studio apartment. Including utilities, furniture and other expenses related to the apartment, you can easily pay a total of about &lt;strong&gt;$40,000&lt;/strong&gt; per year if you want &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rentcafe.com/average-rent-market-trends/us/ny/manhattan/&quot;&gt;your own apartment in Lower Manhattan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meaning I saved about &lt;strong&gt;$14,000&lt;/strong&gt; by going nomad, while having far less responsibilities, as well as get to see new places and neighborhoods each month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;airbnbs&quot;&gt;Airbnbs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the times I lived in Airbnbs in NYC, my experience with it has been pretty good so far. The check-in usually works by picking up the key from a KeyCafe in a nearby Deli. This part is quite tricky, as I have to enter the Deli with all my stuff, and then climb the stairs as most older buildings in NYC don’t have an elevator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/nomad/airbnb-history.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friends working at Airbnb are happy about the fees I pay on each booking :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that has proven extremely useful is using the best travel credit card you can get: By receiving 4.5% cash-back for each travel-related purchase, I get over &lt;strong&gt;$1,000 for free&lt;/strong&gt; every year by living in Airbnbs and using my credit card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/nomad/boat.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a few nights I stayed on a boat in New York through Airbnb, costing the same as all my other Airbnbs per night (note: it’s the small one in front).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/nomad/working-desk2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One highlight was a 2 weeks trip to Taipei together with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/taquitos&quot;&gt;@taquitos&lt;/a&gt; to work together, instead of meeting in San Francisco or New York.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conferences&quot;&gt;Conferences&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When being invited to speak at conferences, the conference organizers cover the hotel during your stay. Every night they cover saves me about $100 (assuming the SF/NYC rent prices), as I don’t have to pay my lease during that time. I usually combine multiple conferences on one multi-week trip and cover the hotel nights in-between instead of flying back and forth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;friends--happiness&quot;&gt;Friends &amp;amp; Happiness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/krausefx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/nomad/friends.jpg&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; width=&quot;310&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 20px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is something I talked about in the &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/going-nomad&quot;&gt;original nomad blog post&lt;/a&gt;: If you travel to a new city every other week, it’s going to be really difficult to build up close relationships with friends. That’s why I’ve been a big fan of the current setup: I stay in the same city, but move within it, meaning I get to hang out with the same group of people and spend quality time with them, while still having the benefits of a nomad life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since February 2018 I’m tracking my mood &amp;amp; happiness level 3 times a day, here is the result so far:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/nomad/mood.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 times a day I answer the question on how I’m feeling on a scale from 0 to 6 using my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/KrauseFx/mood&quot;&gt;open source Telegram bot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If today were the last day of my life, would I want to do what I am about to do today?” And whenever the answer has been “No” for too many days in a row, I know I need to change something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As everything in life, things are an up and down. The overall trend is visible as the green line, which is clearly a wave going in cycles. I marked the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;I'm feeling average&lt;/code&gt; level as orange. Ideally I don’t want any of the other colored lines to go below it. One-off values below it are common as seen as the light gray dots. Looking at the graph, every time the blue line dropped below the orange one, something happened that affected my overall mood. It’s good to see the line usually recovering back to normal rather fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fitness&quot;&gt;Fitness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been spending a lot of time working on reaching my fitness goals in the year of 2018, and it has worked surprisingly well:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The last years I did mostly power lifting, so I also gained a good amount of fat. As of February 2018 I wanted to work on appearance and wanted to focus on a clean diet as well as a different workout&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I lost 25lbs (11 kg) within 6 months while keeping a good amount of muscle mass&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I stopped cooking at home, as finding things at a new kitchen and setting everything up doesn’t work if you’re only staying for a week or two. Instead, 100% of my meals were from the Google office and eating out. This makes following a strict nutrition plan a lot more difficult, as I can’t track the exact macros, and don’t have control over the fat that’s used&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I managed to drop my body fat percentage by 6%, to a total of 8.9% according to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nhs.uk/conditions/dexa-scan/&quot;&gt;DEXA scan&lt;/a&gt; (the only decent-precise way to measure body fat)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I travel my own &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00D5FGR2C/ref=oh_aui_search_detailpage?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;travel scale&lt;/a&gt; to track my body weight every morning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I track everything I eat in MyFitnessPal. Tracking food is a game changer, no matter how well you think you eat, MyFitnessPal will most likely tell you otherwise if you haven’t tracked macros in the past (very thankful my fitness trainer &lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/faronsalisbury&quot;&gt;@faronsalisbury&lt;/a&gt; convinced me to do this)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I usually stock up the fridge with a few essentials, being frozen chicken breast, frozen veggies, black beans, oatmeal and some diet sodas.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Having a routine, and your own place with your own kitchen would make reaching fitness goals easier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whereisfelixtoday&quot;&gt;whereisfelix.today&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A joke project I started back in February 2018: &lt;a href=&quot;https://whereisfelix.today&quot;&gt;whereisfelix.today&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As people in SF/NYC travel around a lot, it’s often difficult to schedule time to meet. Most conversations start with “Hey, when are you back in New York?”. I decided to buy this domain for fun, and have my travel schedule up there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reactions from people when I send them this link are great. I now even have a shortcut on my Mac to type the domain for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://whereisfelix.today&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/nomad/whereisfelix1.png&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;margin-right: -20px; margin-left: -20px;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/nomad/whereisfelix2.png&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;margin-right: -40px; margin-left: -20px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a real-time dashboard of which city I’m currently in, as well as my upcoming travel schedule. Over the last few months I added more and more information to it, including my current mood (which I track with my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/krausefx/mood&quot;&gt;open source Telegram bot&lt;/a&gt;), the macros I ate today, current time, weight and most recent Instagram pictures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used this project as an excuse to learn some things I haven’t used yet: TypeScript, node.js, Angular, and immutable deployments on &lt;a href=&quot;https://zeit.co&quot;&gt;Zeit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The website itself is also &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/krausefx/whereisfelix.today&quot;&gt;open source on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;downsides&quot;&gt;Downsides&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Turns out, government entities and banks are not so familiar with the concept of digital nomads and are not happy when you tell them you don’t have a home address, nor a utility bill or lease agreement. I’m happy I opened all my financial accounts before this change, as it for sure makes things a little more complicated.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Moving around is exhausting, even if you only carry your suitcase + bag. It still takes about 3 hours to move to a new place.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Everything around fitness, from tracking, cooking to buying food in bulk, to meal-prepping would be a lot easier if I wasn’t a nomad&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Media: I don’t watch a lot of TV, nor play a lot of games, but when I do, it’s annoying to get things up and running. Setting things up takes time, and is usually not worth it. I end up watching Netflix just on my phone, and the only console I have is the Nintendo Switch, as I can play without a TV. The same goes for the sound system: I ended up buying my own &lt;a href=&quot;https://smile.amazon.com/Bose-SoundLink-Portable-Long-Lasting-Bluetooth/dp/B06XCW4VFS/ref=sr_1_17?s=electronics&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1541758490&amp;amp;sr=1-17&quot;&gt;portable speaker&lt;/a&gt; I bring with me so I don’t have to deal with learning how each apartment’s sound system works.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It takes a lot of time finding good Airbnbs, lots of hosts don’t respond and you have to plan ahead&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I miss having a proper working setup outside the office: Having an external monitor and a standing desk is something I really learned to appreciate. As shown in the pictures in this post, I carry around a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.therooststand.com/&quot;&gt;mobile MacBook stand&lt;/a&gt;, as well as Apple keyboard, trackpad and mouse.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/nomad/suitcases2.jpg&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 20px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living out of a suitcase comes with its challenges. You learn a lot about yourself, what you need, what you appreciate and how to optimize your life around not owning a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really appreciate the chance to re-invent your daily schedule every time you move. You learn a lot about different kinds of apartments and what you make use of most often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Staying in one city, and moving within it has proven very efficient when it comes to being productive, getting to know new people as well as staying close with your friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is possible to reach your fitness goals without a fixed routine, and without cooking, however it does make things a little more challenging. Having a gym membership with a chain that has multiple locations in your city is key 🔑.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m really happy I made the switch, it has been a great journey so far.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="digital" /><category term="nomad" /><summary type="html">I got rid of all my stuff and live off only a suitcase - staying in Airbnbs to explore different areas 🏡🚀 excited to live nomad life pic.twitter.com/nWGf7AFKiZ&amp;mdash; Felix Krause (@KrauseFx) November 9, 2017</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">iOS-factor: A methodology for building high-quality iOS apps</title><link href="https://krausefx.com//blog/ios-factor" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="iOS-factor: A methodology for building high-quality iOS apps" /><published>2018-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://krausefx.com//blog/ios-factor</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://krausefx.com//blog/ios-factor">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ios-factor.com&quot;&gt;iOS-factor&lt;/a&gt; was inspired by the famous &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.12factor.net/&quot;&gt;twelve-factor app framework&lt;/a&gt;, a methodology to write high-quality web services. &lt;a href=&quot;https://ios-factor.com&quot;&gt;iOS-factor&lt;/a&gt; uses the same structure and similar principles, re-written and applied to the iOS app development processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past 10 years, the iOS development process has shifted drastically:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;from supporting a single device to a wide range of available iOS-powered iPhones and iPads and various platforms like tvOS and watchOS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;from manually including git submodules to using dependency managers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;from iOS apps mostly running locally on-device, to iOS apps heavily relying on backend services&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;from iOS app review times of more than 2 weeks to less than a day&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;from installing an app on your phone using iTunes to distributing apps through the official TestFlight channel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;from uploading 5 screenshots per language to iTunes Connect to 110 per language, as well as app previews&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;from plain Objective-C/C++ apps to a mix of languages including JavaScript&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;from slow releases whenever something is ready, to shipping every single week&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;from full releases to A/B testing, slow rollouts and automatic regression detection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-ios-factor&quot;&gt;What’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://ios-factor.com&quot;&gt;iOS-factor&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ios-factor.com&quot;&gt;iOS-factor&lt;/a&gt; is a project I started in May 2018. It aims to provide a collection of best practices for building high-end iOS applications. Each topic is covered by a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;factor&lt;/code&gt;, which describes an ideal state of how a certain category of the iOS app development process could look like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to certain limitations (like Xcode running only on macOS) not all requirements can be fulfilled. This project aims to define goals, as well as the best current approaches to solve some of the challenges we’re facing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ios-factor.com&quot;&gt;iOS-factor&lt;/a&gt; is all about the bigger-picture iOS app development processes and architecture decisions and will not cover any language specific challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a living project, maintained by the iOS development community. You can find the full source on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/iOS-factor/iOS-factor.com&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and update existing pages or add new factors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: center; font-size: 140%&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ios-factor.com&quot;&gt;Open iOS-factor.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="ios" /><summary type="html">iOS-factor was inspired by the famous twelve-factor app framework, a methodology to write high-quality web services. iOS-factor uses the same structure and similar principles, re-written and applied to the iOS app development processes.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">iOS apps should be inside a network sandbox</title><link href="https://krausefx.com//blog/ios-app-network-sandboxing" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="iOS apps should be inside a network sandbox" /><published>2018-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://krausefx.com//blog/ios-app-network-sandboxing</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://krausefx.com//blog/ios-app-network-sandboxing">&lt;h2 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With my recent publications, most importantly “&lt;a href=&quot;https://krausefx.com/blog/trusting-sdks&quot;&gt;Trusting SDKs&lt;/a&gt;” it became clear that hijacked or malicious iOS apps cause major security and privacy risks for users, and allow attackers to reach a high number of users through a single point of failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the times, the consequences of those attacks are about data:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Usernames and passwords&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Location data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Facial data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Advertising data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Address book entries&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Payment information (e.g. credit cards)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Other personal information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice how sandboxes in software are designed to keep data inside that box (in the form of a filesystem), but for some reason they stop when it comes to network requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If an attacker manages to hijack an iOS app, the first thing they would do is sent the collected data to some server in their control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;idea&quot;&gt;Idea&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially just &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/KrauseFx/status/962116690233339904&quot;&gt;tweeting my shower thoughts&lt;/a&gt; and reaching 300 likes &amp;amp; 50 RTs, this idea grew more and more:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;jekyll-twitter-plugin&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Apple should require every iOS app to define a list of web hosts that should be accessible, all other web requests will fail:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;- If an app gets compromised no data can leak&lt;br /&gt;- It forces the use of SFSafariViewController&lt;br /&gt;- Users should be able to see the host list&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Felix Krause (@KrauseFx) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/KrauseFx/status/962116690233339904?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;February 10, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;app-transport-security&quot;&gt;App Transport Security&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2016/06/14/apple-will-require-https-connections-for-ios-apps-by-the-end-of-2016/&quot;&gt;WWDC 2016 Apple announced ATS&lt;/a&gt;, an iOS 9 feature to enforce the use of HTTPs across all iOS apps. It was said to be made mandatory by end of 2016, however the deadline was moved to an undefined date. The idea makes perfect sense: All the infrastructure and tools around HTTPs encryption people already have with their web browsers to verify the security on websites, don’t work on the iOS platform. If you use your banking or dating app, how can you as a user be sure the company didn’t mess things up? &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/02/grindr-sends-hiv-status-to-third-parties-and-some-personal-data-unencrypted/&quot;&gt;It’s not like it happened before&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;web-vs-ios&quot;&gt;Web vs iOS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the web, &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/web/updates/2016/10/avoid-not-secure-warn&quot;&gt;browsers started marking HTTP websites as “Not Secure”&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_Strict_Transport_Security&quot;&gt;HSTS is built into browsers to force HTTPs for certain hosts&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/https-everywhere/gcbommkclmclpchllfjekcdonpmejbdp?hl=en&quot;&gt;people use HTTPSEverywhere to enforce HTTPs connection across more hosts&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/ublock-origin/cjpalhdlnbpafiamejdnhcphjbkeiagm?hl=en&quot;&gt;people use uBlock to block certain tracking and ad widgets that slow down websites&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On iOS, you install and use an app, and hope that the app developer uses proper encryption, securely stores your personal information, and doesn’t use any sketchy SDKs that you wouldn’t trust yourself. If you don’t agree with something (e.g. an Analytics SDK), there is nothing you can do about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;proposal&quot;&gt;Proposal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-1&quot;&gt;Step 1:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finish the ATS plans. It’s been 2 years now, enough time for app developers to update their apps. Allow developers to file for an exception, and mark them accordingly on the App Store page with a badge of shame (similar to how &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/web/updates/2016/10/avoid-not-secure-warn&quot;&gt;Chrome marks all non HTTPs websites&lt;/a&gt; nowadays)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-2&quot;&gt;Step 2:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/sandboxing.png&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; style=&quot;margin: 15px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Introduce the concept of network sandboxes. Each app should define a list of hostnames they are allowed to access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine a ride-sharing app having access to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;my-ride-sharing-app.com&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;stripe.com&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;google-analytics.com&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;maps.google.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This list serves multiple purposes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The app can only access those hosts. Meaning if an SDK is malicious or your app got hijacked in some way, they can’t access the scary internet and leak the user’s data.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The app review team will see a list as they approve the app. At the same time, they can see a diff of the hosts between app releases&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The user should have a way to see that list as part of the App Store page&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the future we could even put the user in control by distinguishing between primary hosts (e.g. twitter.com) that are needed to have the app running, and secondary hosts (e.g. random-analytics-service.com). This however would come with many implications when it comes to revenue models of the majority of mobile apps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, exceptions should be possible, third party browsers should exist, and some apps might have to support so many hosts that they can’t follow those rules. And that’s okay, those apps will be marked as “Can access any host” as a little warning in the App Store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the above doesn’t solve all the problems, it is a good first step into the right direction. We’ll run into problems, and we’ll solve them. It’s a necessary change for the mobile ecosystem, catching up with where we’re already at with web browsers nowadays.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="privacy" /><category term="security" /><summary type="html">Background</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Going nomad</title><link href="https://krausefx.com//blog/going-nomad" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Going nomad" /><published>2018-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://krausefx.com//blog/going-nomad</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://krausefx.com//blog/going-nomad">&lt;div class=&quot;jekyll-twitter-plugin&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;I got rid of all my stuff and live off only a suitcase - staying in Airbnbs to explore different areas 🏡🚀 excited to live nomad life &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/nWGf7AFKiZ&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/nWGf7AFKiZ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Felix Krause (@KrauseFx) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/KrauseFx/status/928718106876305408?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;November 9, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/one-year-nomad&quot;&gt;One Year Nomad post from 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I moved to San Francisco summer 2015 to join Twitter. I lived in a furnished apartment for my first year, which I really enjoyed, as I didn’t have to buy all the essentials myself after moving across the globe into a new country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After my 1 year lease, I decided to do what “grown-ups” are supposed to do: get their own apartment, buy furniture, decorate the place, and make it your home. After living in my little studio for about 1.5 years, I noticed a few things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In 2017 I only spent about 200 nights in my apartment, causing me to still pay about 5 months worth of San Francisco rent without actually living there (the average monthly lease for a studio apartment is about $3,000 + utilities, resulting in about $15,000 of my after tax money being lost)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While I enjoy having my own space, I never invested enough time and effort into making it nice: Until the day I moved out after 18 months, I still didn’t have enough closets for all my things and I had my clothes piled up in some corner&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I didn’t like being bound to one location in the city. In particular, in the common case of getting acquired by another company (#justSFthings), your commute changes, and you can’t just move around&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I didn’t like the fact that I was always surrounded by the same places and things became routine. Same subway station, same spots you walk by every day, same views, same commute, etc. after a month it gets boring and I need a change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/nomad/SF-Map.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-idea&quot;&gt;The idea&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since I first started reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://levels.io/&quot;&gt;@levelsio’s blog&lt;/a&gt; in 2014, about living out of &lt;a href=&quot;https://levels.io/carry-on-world-travel/&quot;&gt;just a backpack&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://levels.io/remote-working-is-the-future/&quot;&gt;traveling across the world, while working on his own startups&lt;/a&gt;, I was fascinated by the idea. However I always assumed it doesn’t work if you have a full-time job at a large company like Twitter or Google.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014 was also the time I met &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/orta&quot;&gt;@orta&lt;/a&gt;, who told me about his first year in New York City, where he lived in a different neighborhood in a random Airbnb each month. This allowed him to see what NYC has to offer, and what area he liked the most. I loved the idea, and kind of knew I want to do this at some point in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only in October 2017 I realized that combining those two things might actually just work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;making-the-move&quot;&gt;Making the move&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/nomad/suitcases.jpg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 20px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After living in San Francisco for 2.5 years, I wanted a change. With my lease ending in October, I decided to reduce my life to just&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 suitcase&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 carry-on luggage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 backpack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and lived in an Airbnb in San Francisco until the winter holidays, for which I went back home to Austria. I got really lucky with my SF Airbnb, as I got it from &lt;a href=&quot;https://zeusliving.com/&quot;&gt;Zeus Living&lt;/a&gt; a company that rents out apartments for people like me: rent a place per month, all utilities included, and enough space with a desk to get work done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the last 6 months I’ve lived the nomad life, with just the things listed above. So far I’ve stayed in 6 different neighborhoods in NYC, 2 areas in SF and spent time with my family in Austria for New Year’s. While I plan flights ahead of time due to costs, I don’t book places longer than a month ahead, something that took some time getting used to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;spending-time-in-a-single-city&quot;&gt;Spending time in a single city&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While being a different city each month might sound like a dream to many people, I learned it comes with many downsides:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s hard to build up a social circle of close friends&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s hard to really get to know a city, and make use of all the things it has to offer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s hard to learn more about the culture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cities change with seasons, a summer is usually quite different than a winter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s stressful changing cities too often&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year I &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/krausefx/speaking&quot;&gt;spoke at conferences in 9 cities&lt;/a&gt;. I knew I wanted to fly less in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In January 2018, we started the new &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fastlane/ci&quot;&gt;fastlane.ci project&lt;/a&gt;, which requires us to work closer with other Google teams, that are partially based in New York. I used that opportunity to “move” to NYC. So while I move to a different Airbnb every week, I do so within the same city. I grew up in a village with a population of less than 2,000, with not a single traffic light. Living in New York has been an amazing experience, with almost as many people living here, as in the whole country of Austria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, this seems like the perfect balance for me personally: Not getting bored by day to day routine (e.g. same commute) by moving to a new Airbnb every week, but also being able to hang out with the same friends, and get to know the whole city. Long term, I’ll switch to a monthly cycle for even less overhead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;frequently-asked-questions&quot;&gt;Frequently asked questions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-do-you-handle-physical-mail&quot;&gt;How do you handle physical mail?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online orders&lt;/strong&gt;: I’m lucky that I can use the Google office to order from Amazon, and pick them up at the end of the work day. It’s offered in most major cities, and even allows me to order something for a specific location. For example: When I flew to Amsterdam I ordered an umbrella to the office, ready for me to pick up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Letters&lt;/strong&gt;: I use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.virtualpostmail.com/&quot;&gt;VirtualPostMail&lt;/a&gt; service. They scan your letters, and sends them to you via email. If you need the original, you can tell them to forward them to your current address (or office in my case)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;money&quot;&gt;Money&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first thought was: Staying in Airbnbs must be more expensive than having my own place! For multiple reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Short term leases have to charge more to account for the vacant nights&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Airbnbs are furnished, and include some basic services and utilities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Airbnb charges a pretty hefty fee for each booking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Circling back to the number of days I’m &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; at home for about 5 months each year, I realized that I don’t pay my (SF/NYC) rent when:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I speak at a conference, and the organizers cover the hotel costs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I go on vacation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I go back home&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I crash on a friend’s couch / extra bed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google plans a team-offsite in a different location and covers the accommodation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I take a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Red-eye_flight&quot;&gt;red eye flight&lt;/a&gt; (a flight that leaves at about midnight, and lands in the morning)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every night I don’t need to pay for my own place, I save about $100 after-tax money (NYC/SF)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;do-you-keep-any-physical-memories&quot;&gt;Do you keep any physical memories&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can either ask your parents nicely to keep your things, or you can rent storage somewhere to keep it. I decided to bring my things back home to Austria, by just having an extra bag with me the first time I flew back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-did-you-get-rid-of-so-much-stuff&quot;&gt;How did you get rid of so much stuff?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t care about physical things. If I were to lose all my devices, or all my clothes today, I’d buy new ones (probably the same ones). So getting rid of things was rather easy, and I personally never understood why it’s difficult, unless there are certain memories attached.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All I did was: Do I really need this? If the answer wasn’t an immediate yes, it’s a no. If I wanted to keep the “memory”, I made sure to take a picture before giving it away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created a spreadsheet with all the things I give away, and shared it with my friends on Facebook, from furniture, to kitchen stuff, to light bulbs, and I got “rid” of everything, as 2 of my friends just moved to a new place, and needed almost everything. The remaining things I donated or threw away if it wasn’t usable any more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went from&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/nomad/diff.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is tricky though to buy new stuff, since I need to get rid of something else, for every single new item I buy. While my suitcases still have some space left, the weight limit of 22kg of most airlines is what I have to be careful about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-do-you-keep-things-organized&quot;&gt;How do you keep things organized?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those &lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.eaglecreek.com/packit-cube-set/d/1322&quot;&gt;travel cubes&lt;/a&gt; have been pretty useful, I got a lot of them, for shirts, socks, underwear, electronics, etc. and can recommend them to anyone traveling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;did-you-buy-any-travel-gear-for-this&quot;&gt;Did you buy any travel gear for this?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/nomad/ordered.jpg&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 20px&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, there are some really cool things out there, that made my life easier:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bose.com/en_us/products/speakers/portable_speakers/soundlink-revolve-plus-bundle.html&quot;&gt;Portable Bose SoundLink Revolve+&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.therooststand.com&quot;&gt;Roost Stand&lt;/a&gt; (MacBook stand for ergonomic working wherever you are in combination with Bluetooth keyboard + trackpad)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.eaglecreek.com/packit-cube-set/d/1322&quot;&gt;Travel cubes&lt;/a&gt; to keep things organized&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00D5FGR2C/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o01_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Travel scale&lt;/a&gt; (I’m into fitness, and started tracking my weight every morning)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;is-that-minimalism-life&quot;&gt;Is that “Minimalism Life”?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve read a bit about this topic, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@coolasspuppy/200-things-dfa3d5034cd7&quot;&gt;a great blog post of my friend about owning 200 things&lt;/a&gt;. I love the concept of owning just the things you really need, and forget the rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also watched the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netflix.com/title/80114460&quot;&gt;“Minimalism” documentary on Netflix&lt;/a&gt;, which covers some of the concepts. Personally I don’t want to count things, or reduce life in areas I don’t want to. For example, I still carry around a rather high number of shoes with me, just because I like having the right shoes for the right occasion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d argue the goal is to live a normal day-to-day life, when going to work or hanging out with friends, while still being very flexible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;security-concerns&quot;&gt;Security concerns&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s something I’ve been thinking more about recently: Breaking into an Airbnb is probably super easy, just stay in a place, copy the key and then steal from the next person, with the next person probably blaming the host or cleaning staff. Unfortunately it’s not common for Airbnbs to have a safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I generally don’t own anything of real value, besides my MacBook&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I don’t leave anything valuable in my Airbnb but put them in the Google office instead&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All of my documents are stored online&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hourly backups on different continents, using hard drives and custom cloud backup solutions, all end to end encrypted, on a total of 5 different locations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Even if I were to lose 100% of my things including all my devices, I have a clear recovery path where I can recover my complete online identity, documents and everything else within less than 24 hours. For security reasons I can’t share more about this specific topic, but I can recommend everyone to draw a map of dependencies between the services/software/hardware you use, and how you can recover them step by step.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-else-is-nice-about-not-having-a-fixed-lease&quot;&gt;What else is nice about not having a fixed lease?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you stay at a place for just a week, you’ll never have to clean the apartment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You learn how other people live day to day, e.g. how they set up their rooms and get a good idea of what you enjoy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You learn more about yourself, like what things are important to you when it comes to having a living space&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When you own a home, you have to deal with maintenance, repairs and other things quite often. When renting an apartment building, at least some things are being taken care of by the owners. If you stay in Airbnb, there is literally nothing you have to worry about, if something doesn’t work, you notify the host and that’s it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/nomad/taipei.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote this post in Taipei, Taiwan, where I work remotely from the Taipei Google office for 2 weeks before heading to San Francisco.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being able to escape the cold winter feels amazing 😎&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/one-year-nomad&quot;&gt;One Year Nomad post from 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="digital" /><category term="nomad" /><summary type="html">I got rid of all my stuff and live off only a suitcase - staying in Airbnbs to explore different areas 🏡🚀 excited to live nomad life pic.twitter.com/nWGf7AFKiZ&amp;mdash; Felix Krause (@KrauseFx) November 9, 2017</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How I use Twitter</title><link href="https://krausefx.com//blog/how-i-use-twitter" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How I use Twitter" /><published>2018-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://krausefx.com//blog/how-i-use-twitter</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://krausefx.com//blog/how-i-use-twitter">&lt;h2 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most people, using the official Twitter client works fine. It’s optimized to show you new content you might be interested in, makes it easy to follow new users, and shows content that might be most relevant to you first. If you have an engineering mindset, chances are you want to be in control of what you see in your timeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use Twitter to stay up to date with certain people. I want to hear about new projects or new content they published, new blog posts, thoughts of them, etc. I’m not interested in hearing political opinions, sport scores, etc, which I already have Facebook for. If I follow someone, I’ll read every single tweet from them. For the last 5 years, I didn’t miss a tweet in my timeline, so I have to be very careful about who to follow, and what content to see. So I set out to customize Twitter to achieve that goal, and to only see about 50-75 tweets per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;solution&quot;&gt;Solution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using &lt;a href=&quot;https://tapbots.com/tweetbot/&quot;&gt;Tweetbot&lt;/a&gt; for the last few years, the technique described below might work with other third party Twitter clients also.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;muted-keywords&quot;&gt;Muted Keywords&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very basic list of words, that as soon as a tweet contains one of them, it will be hidden, examples include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;headphone jack&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;drake&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;podcast&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;president&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;muted-users&quot;&gt;Muted users&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stopped using this feature, now that I use secret lists to follow people (see below), and disabled RTs. Muting users for a given time period or forever is useful for a few situations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some users in your timeline might promote a product, so you can mute that product&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If a user is at a conference/event you’re not interested in, you can mute them for a few days&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;muted-regexes&quot;&gt;Muted Regexes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A very powerful feature of Tweetbot is to define a regex to hide tweet. I use it to hide annoying jokes like&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;remember \w+&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;german word for \w+&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;\w+ is the new \w+&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;or to hide tweets from people that think we’re interested about their airplane delays or #sports&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;(virgin|Virgin|@United|delta|Delta|JetBlue|jetblue)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;twitter.com/i/moments&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For every #sports #event there are also custom-made mute filters (truncated): &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;(?#World Cup)(?i)((?# Terms)(Brazil\s*2014|FIFA|World\s*Cup|Soccer|F(oo|u)tbal)|(?# Chants)(go a l |[^\w](ole\s*){2,})|(?# Teams)(#(B....&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hide-all-mentions&quot;&gt;Hide all mentions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This very much changed my whole timeline (for the better). Turns out, I follow people for their announcements, what they work on, what they’re doing, what they’re thinking about, etc. I actually don’t want to see 2 people communicating publicly using @ mentions, unless it’s a topic I’m interested in. So I started hiding all tweets that start with an &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@&lt;/code&gt; symbol using a simple Tweetbot regex&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;^@&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I want to see responses to a tweet, I’d swipe to the left side, and see all replies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;muted-clients&quot;&gt;Muted Clients&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Muting certain clients has been amazing, very easy to set up and cleans up your timeline a lot. Some of the clients I mute:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buffer (to avoid “content marketing”, so many companies make the mistake of tweeting the same posts every week or so using Buffer)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;IFTTT (lots of people use that to auto-post not original content)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spotify&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Foursquare (I follow friends on Swarm already, no need to see it twice)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Facebook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/tweetbot_filters.png&quot; width=&quot;220&quot; style=&quot;float: right; margin-left: 20px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;secret-lists&quot;&gt;Secret Lists&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One issue I had was to balance the number of tweets in my timeline, and then also being polite and following friends. To avoid the whole “Why are you not following me?” conversation, I now use a private list to follow about 300 people only. I &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/krausefx/twitter-unfollow&quot;&gt;open sourced the script&lt;/a&gt; I used to migrate all the people I used to follow over to a private list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;disable-rts&quot;&gt;Disable RTs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has been a great change: As described above, I follow people for what they do, what they think of, and what they’re working on. Some people have the habit of RTing content that might be interesting, but not relevant to why I want to stay subscribed to their tweets. On Tweetbot, you can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;muting-hashtags&quot;&gt;Muting hashtags&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/tweetbot_filters_2.png&quot; width=&quot;220&quot; style=&quot;float: right; margin-left: 20px; margin-top: 20px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thank everyone for using hashtags for certain events, making it easy to hide them from my timeline :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;disadvantages-of-this-approach&quot;&gt;Disadvantages of this approach&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the newer Twitter features don’t have an API, and therefore can’t be offered by Tweetbot. This includes Polls, Moments and Group DMs. Since I don’t want to miss group DMs, I set up email notifications for Twitter DMs, and set up a Gmail filter to auto-archive emails that are not from group DMs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent quite some time optimizing that workflow, and it’s very specific, and probably not useful for most people. I try to minimize my time on social media, I only browse my Twitter feed when I have a few minutes to kill on the go. Meaning I work through my timeline only on my iPhone, and reply to mentions and DMs only on my Mac. I don’t want to come across uninterested, I do follow people on Facebook, I do read news and stay up to date. Twitter is a place for very specific content for me, and I want to keep using it as that.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="twitter" /><summary type="html">Background</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">iOS Privacy: Track website activities, steal user data &amp;amp; credentials and add your own ads to any website in your iOS app</title><link href="https://krausefx.com//blog/follow-user" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="iOS Privacy: Track website activities, steal user data &amp; credentials and add your own ads to any website in your iOS app" /><published>2018-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://krausefx.com//blog/follow-user</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://krausefx.com//blog/follow-user">&lt;h2 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;video&quot; style=&quot;float: right; margin-left: 20px&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/ZIogd0kv80c&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;170&quot; height=&quot;350&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most iOS apps need to show external web content at some point. Apple provided multiple ways for a developer to do so, the official ones are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;launch-a-url-in-safari&quot;&gt;Launch a URL in Safari&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will use the app switcher to move your own app into the background. This way, the user has their own browser (Safari), with their session and content blocker, browser plugins (e.g. 1Password), etc. As launching Safari puts your app into the background, many app developers are worried the user doesn’t come back to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the first video to see how this looks in action ➡️&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;use-in-app-sfsafariviewcontroller&quot;&gt;Use in-app &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/documentation/safariservices/sfsafariviewcontroller&quot;&gt;SFSafariViewController&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many third party iOS apps use this approach (e.g. Tweetbot).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;video&quot; style=&quot;float: right; margin-left: 20px;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/EPH5XGbigJU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;170&quot; height=&quot;350&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It allows an app developer to use the built-in Safari with all its features, without making the user leave your application. It features all the Safari features, but from within your application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the second video to see how this looks in action ➡️&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;current-state-with-larger-social-network-apps&quot;&gt;Current state with larger social network apps&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many larger iOS apps re-implemented their own in-app web browser. While this was necessary many years ago, nowadays it’s not only not required any more, it actually adds a major risk to the end-user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those custom in-app browsers usually use their own UI elements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Custom address bar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Custom SSL indicator&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Custom share button&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Custom reload button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/browser/browser.png&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; style=&quot;float: right; margin-left: 30px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;problems-with-custom-in-app-browsers&quot;&gt;Problems with custom in-app browsers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If an app renders their own &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/documentation/webkit/wkwebview&quot;&gt;WKWebView&lt;/a&gt;, they not only cause inconvenience for the user, but they actually put them at serious risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;convenience&quot;&gt;Convenience&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;user-session&quot;&gt;User session&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user’s login session isn’t available, meaning if you get a link to e.g. an Amazon product, you now have to login and enter your 2-factor authentication code to purchase a product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;browser-extensions&quot;&gt;Browser extensions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the user has browser extensions (like password managers), they won’t have access to them in a custom in-app browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;deep-linking&quot;&gt;Deep linking&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deep linking itself has multiple open issues on the iOS platform. By using a custom in-app browser, it adds an extra layer that doesn’t work well with deep linking. Instead of opening the Amazon app when tapping on an Amazon link in “Social Media App X”, it opens the product in a plain web-view, with no login session, and no way to open the product in the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;content-blockers&quot;&gt;Content blockers&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the user has content blockers installed, they’re not being used by custom in-app browsers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;bookmarks&quot;&gt;Bookmarks&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/browser/browser-dialog.png&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; style=&quot;float: right; margin-left: 30px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no way for the user to store the current URL in their bookmarks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;share-a-website&quot;&gt;Share a website&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apps use this opportunity to force their users to use whatever “social features” they think are useful to them. Usually that means locking the user into their ecosystem, and not allowing people to share the content on the platform of their choice. There should be an explicit App Store rule against this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;security--privacy&quot;&gt;Security &amp;amp; Privacy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using a custom in-app browser, allows the app developer to inject &lt;strong&gt;ANY&lt;/strong&gt; JavaScript code into the website the user visits. This means, any content, any data and any input that is shown or stored on the website is accessible to the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;analytics&quot;&gt;Analytics&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is basically the main reason why in-app browsers are still a thing: It allows the app maintainer to inject additional analytics code, without telling the user. This way, the app’s developer can track the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How long does the user visit the linked website?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How fast does the user scroll?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Which links does the user open, and how long do they stay on each of them?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Combined with &lt;a href=&quot;https://krausefx.com/blog/ios-privacy-watchuser-access-both-iphone-cameras-any-time-your-app-is-running&quot;&gt;watch.user&lt;/a&gt;, the app can record you while you browse third party websites, or even use the iPhone X face sensor to parse your face&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Every single tap, swipe or any other gesture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Device movements, GPS location (if granted) and any other granted iOS sensor, while the app is still in the foreground.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;user-credentials&quot;&gt;User credentials&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any app with an in-app browser can easily steal the user’s email address, passwords and two-factor authentication codes. They can do that by injecting JavaScript code that bridges the data over to the app, or directly to a remote host. This is simple, it’s basically code like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-javascript highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;email&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;document&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;getElementById&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;email&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;value&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;password&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;document&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;getElementById&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;password&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;value&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s all that’s needed: just inject the code above to every website, run it on every user’s key stroke, and you’ll get a nice list of email addresses and passwords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To run JavaScript in your own web view, you can just use&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-ruby highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;NSString&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;script&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;@&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;document.getElementById('password').value&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;self&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;evaluateJavaScript&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;:script&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;completionHandler&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;:^&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;id&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;result&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;NSError&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;error&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}];&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;user-data&quot;&gt;User data&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the user is logged in, you also get access to the full HTML DOM + JavaScript data &amp;amp; events, which means you have full access to whatever the user sees. This includes things like your emails, your Amazon order history, your friend list, or whatever other data/website you access from an in-app web view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;https&quot;&gt;HTTPs&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually the web browser has a standardised way of indicating the SSL certificate next to the browser’s URL. In the case of custom in-app browsers, the SSL logo is being added by the app’s author, meaning you trust the app’s maintainer to only show the logo if it’s actually a valid SSL certificate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ads&quot;&gt;Ads&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Custom in-app browsers allow all app developers to inject their own ad system into any website that’s shown as part of their app. But not only that, they can &lt;strong&gt;replace&lt;/strong&gt; the ads identifier of ads that are already shown on the website, so that the revenue goes directly to them, instead of the website owner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;and-more&quot;&gt;And more&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are just some of the things that immediately come to my mind, every time I use an in-app browser, there are probably a lot more evil things a company &lt;a href=&quot;https://krausefx.com/blog/trusting-sdks&quot;&gt;or SDK&lt;/a&gt; could be doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-can-we-solve-this&quot;&gt;How can we solve this?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reject apps that don’t use &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/documentation/safariservices/sfsafariviewcontroller&quot;&gt;SFSafariViewController&lt;/a&gt; or launch Safari directly to show third party website content&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There should be exceptions, e.g. if a webview is used to show parts of the UI, or dynamic content, but it should be illegal to use webviews to show a linked or third party website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also &lt;a href=&quot;https://openradar.appspot.com/radar?id=4963695432040448&quot;&gt;filed a radar for this issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;similar-projects-ive-worked-on&quot;&gt;Similar projects I’ve worked on &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I published more posts on how to access the camera, the user’s location data, their Mac screen and their iCloud password, check out &lt;a href=&quot;/privacy&quot;&gt;krausefx.com/privacy&lt;/a&gt; for more.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="security" /><category term="privacy" /><category term="sdks" /><summary type="html">Background</summary></entry></feed>